Often programming involves more than numbers and arithmetic.
编程经常涉及的不仅仅是数字和算术
There may be situations where you need to work with text.
有时候还需要处理文本
To work with text in Python,
要在 Python 中处理文本
you will need to use a string,
你需要使用字符串
which is an immutable ordered series of characters.
字符串是一系列不可改变的有序字符
More on the immutable ordered part later.
稍后我们会深入讲解不可改变和有序是什么意思
You can create a string by using quotes.
你可以使用引号来创建字符串
Single or double quotes work equally well,
单引号和双引号都可以
although there are some edge cases, which we will work through.
但是有一些极端情况 我们稍后会讲解
In each of these cases I printed the string "hello" and got the output "hello".
在这两种情况下 我都输出了字符串“hello”并获得输出结果“hello”
We can set a variable to be a string the same way we did with numbers.
我们可以像对待数字一样将变量设为一个字符串
Strings can include any characters,
字符串可以包含任何字符
even spaces, punctuation and numbers.
甚至包括空格 标点和数字
However, what do we do when we want quotation marks in our string?
但是 如果我们希望在字符串中包含引号 该怎么办？
Since we use quotation marks to define our strings,
因为我们使用引号来定义字符串
this presents a small problem.
因此就存在一个小小的问题
Here the code doesn't work the way we want it to.
这段代码并不能像我们希望的那样运行
Python offers two solutions to this problem.
Python 提供了两种解决方案
The first is to place the string in single quotes rather than double quotes, like this.
第一种是将字符串放在单引号里 而不是双引号里 就像这样
You can use either type of quote to define strings,
你可以使用任何一种引号来定义字符串
but sometimes you'll need to define a string that includes both single and double quotes.
但有时候你需要定义同时包含单引号和双引号的字符串
What then? In that case,
这时候该怎么办？在这种情况下
you can use the backslash to escape quotes.
可以使用反斜杠来转义引号
Here the string is delimited by single quotes.
此处 字符串用单引号限定
The single quote within the string is preceded by a backslash so that Python
字符串中的单引号前面有个反斜杠
knows that it should be interpreted as part of
这样 Python 便知道应该将其当做字符串的一部分
the string rather than the quote that ends the string.
而不是表示字符串结束的引号
Once our strings are defined,
定义好字符串后
there are a few operations that are used for
我们可以对字符串应用
integers and floats that we can also use for strings.
整型和浮点型数据用到的运算符
For example, we can use the plus sign to put strings together,
例如 我们可以使用加号将字符串放到一起
and we can use multiplication to repeat strings.
并使用乘法来重复字符串
Let's look at an example of each.
我们来分别看一个示例
Here our variables are holding two words.
此处 我们的变量存储了两个单词
We can use the plus sign to concatenate the two strings together and print the result.
我们可以使用加号将这两个字符串连到一起并输出结果
This is fundamentally different from numeric addition.
这与数字相加完全不同
However, notice the two names have been squished together.
注意两个名称连到一起了
We're missing a space.
但是缺少空格
Python is completely literal when working with strings.
Python 在处理字符串时 完全遵守字面意思
We need to explicitly include spaces and
如果我们希望所写的内容有意义
punctuation if we want what we write to make sense.
则需要明确包含空格和标点
This time we got a string that makes sense,
这次 我们获得了有意义的字符串
putting the two words together with a space in between.
将两个单词放到一起 并在中间加个空格
Note that previously I said a white space doesn't matter in
注意 之前我提到 在括号里 例如在 print 语句里
between parentheses in bits of code, like print statements.
空格并不重要
Here with strings, you can see that spaces do matter in between the quotation marks.
这里 对于字符串 可以看出引号中间的空格的确重要
Let's try another mathematical operation.
我们再试试另一个数学运算
Turns out we can use the multiplication operator as well.
实际上我们也可以使用乘法运算符
It repeats the string as many times as you multiply it.
它会按照乘数重复字符串
Here five times.
这里重复了五次
Although addition and multiplication have different applications for strings,
虽然对于字符串来说 加法和乘法具有不同的应用
subtraction and division do not.
但是减法和除法则没有
Here we get an error that a string is an unsupported type for the division operator.
这里 系统提示对于除法运算符来说 字符串是不受支持的类型
A useful function that's built into Python
Python 中有一个实用的内置函数
is Len which can tell us the length of a string.
叫做 len 它可以告诉我们字符串的长度
This is just the number of characters in the string.
表示字符串中的字符数量
Len is like print in that it's a built-in function that
len 就像 print 它是一个内置函数
takes in a value in parentheses to perform an action.
在括号中获得一个值 并执行操作
Len differs from print in that it returns a value that can be stored in a variable.
len 与 print 的区别是它可以返回一个存储在变量中的值
In this example, the Len function outputs to number seven,
在此示例中 函数 len 输出数字 7
which is stored in the Udacity length variable.
然后将 7 存储在 Udacity_length 变量中
Built-in just means Python provides these functions for us.
内置是指 Python 直接为我们提供了这些函数
Later, we'll learn how to define our own functions.
稍后 我们将了解如何定义我们自己的函数